Maxim Lukin

Working student/ Werkstudent

• Address: Erlangen, Germany, 91052

Complete Complete Complete

in LinkedIn: https://linkedin.com/in/maxim-lukin-67635420b

■ ORCID iD: https://orcid.org/0000-0002-8831-3719.



Curriculum vitae

Personal Information

Date of birth: December 17, 1997 in Novokuznetsk, Russia

↑ Nationality: Russian

* Marital status: Unmarried, no children.

Executive Summary

Being a person with a strong mathematical understanding of the methods used in simulation modelling, as well as experience in structural mechanics, I am going to get a master's degree at a German university. I assume it will expand my professional horizons. Also, I am proud to have advanced knowledge of speaking and writing English, and I still continue attending the German courses. I am a flexible person for different projects in all sectors of modelling and structural analysis.

Professional Skills

Finite Element Method (FEM), MATLAB, ANSYS, Stress Analysis, Microsoft Office, Simulation, Writing academic papers and technical reports, C++, AutoCAD, Python, STARK ES, Microsoft SharePoint, LIRA SAPR, Mathematical analysis, LATEX.

Career Objective

Working for Siemens AG would widen my perspectives by giving me incomparable to anything experience in innovative composing and allow me to start my international career. Your company would give me an opportunity to reveal myself as a part of a professional team.

Employment

09/2019 - 10/2020 Junior Engineer | JSC Research Center of Construction ♥ Moscow, Russia

Tasks

- Performed Finite Element static, dynamic analysis of 3D structures
- Estimated of structural components and their links
- Analysed steel elements and their connections
- Prepared and supervised the final versions of technical reports

Successes

- 4 regional and 2 international well passed projects
- Increased the productivity of the analysis team by $\approx 20\%$
- 6 scientific technical reports confirmed by expert review.

Maxim Lukin Page 2

Interships

 $mathred{m} 06/2019 - 09/2019$

Intern Simulation and Structural Mechanics

Laboratory for Automation of Research and Design of Structures

JSC Research Center of Construction (http://en.cstroy.ru)

♀ Moscow, Russia

• Structural Analysis with Finite Element Method

• Simulation of Dynamic Loads

 $mathred{m} 04/2019 - 06/2019$

Intern Wind Impact Simulation

Industrial Research Laboratory for Aerodynamic and Aeroacoustic

Testing of Building Structures

Moscow State University of Civil Engineering ((https://mgsu.ru/en/)

♥ Moscow, Russia

• Evaluation of wind impacts on buildings and structures using physical wind tunnel simulations and numerical simulation.

Education

10/2020 - Present

MSc. in Computational and Applied Mathematics

Friedrich-Alexander University Erlangen-Nürnberg (FAU)

♀ Erlangen, Germany

• Focus Areas: Computational and Applied Mathematics (CAM)

 $mathred{m}09/2019 - 07/2021$

MSc. in Applied Mechanics

Moscow State University of Civil Engineering (MSUCE)

♥ Moscow, Russia

• Focus Areas: Analysis and FEM Simulation

• Thesis: "Study of Industrial Tower Type Supporting Frame on

Wind Impact" (grade: excellent)

mathred 09/2015 - 07/2019

BSc. in Applied Mathematics

Moscow State University of Civil Engineering (MSUCE)

♥ Moscow, Russia

• Focus Areas: Applied Mathematics

• Thesis: "Research of Wind Impact on Rectangular Uncovered Industrial

Frameworks with Equipment or Protecting Screen" (grade: excellent).

Additional Skills & Qualifications

Courses

CodeCademy:

Learn C++, C++ for Programmers, Differential Calculus

LinkedIn:

Simulation for Finite Element Analysis, AutoCAD: Advanced 3D Modeling,

C++ Best Practices for Developers

Mac Languages

Russian

Native speaker

English

Independent (CEFR: C1)

German

Basic (CEFR: A2).

Publications

[1] L. Frishter, M. Lukin: Experimental study of wind impact on multilevel industrial scaffolding, E3S Web of Conferences 157, 06009 (2020), pp. 228-298.

Maxim Lukin Page 3

References

Yuri Zhuk JSC Research Center of Construction | Head of Department

+7499 170-10-80 | laip@tsniisk.ru

Supervisor

Mr. Zhuk supervised my work at Research Center of Construction and supporting

my career at the beginning

Prof. Dr. Lyidmila Frishter University Professor | Moscow State University of Civil Engineering

Frishter LY@mgsu.ru

Academic Advisor

Prof. Dr. Frishter was a valuable contact and guardian during the completion

of my theses.